ZHENG-WEI LIU

<u>LinkedIn</u> | wei.141227@gmail.com | Taipei, Taiwan | (+886) 911946645

Summary

Backend Developer with 2+ years of experience focusing on building multi-tenant SaaS architecture for a logistics fleet management product. Skilled at working effectively and contributing to product ideation in fast-paced Scrum teams. Eager to learn and grow, and to share knowledge with others to create a more knowledgeable and effective team.

Technical Skills

NestJS / Node.js / TypeScript / Rabbitmq / MSSQL / Redis / Docker / Kubernetes / Azure

Experience

Backend Developer, 3drens, Taipei, Taiwan

2022.05 - 2024.03

Teamwork & Collaboration:

- Worked closely with PMs, designers, and Frontend in the Scrum team, and actively contributed to the improvement of core product features such as the ETA algorithm and cargo tracking website design, ensuring a user-centered approach.
- Reduced Backend team development time by 10% and improved API readability and testability for Frontend and QA engineers by automating API documentation generation.
- Enhanced RD team code quality by introducing **SonarQube** into CI, eliminating 100+ bad smells in legacy code.
- Authored technical docs, including HLDs and workflows to enhance team collaboration and knowledge sharing.

Technical Problem-Solving & Impact:

- Maintain and develop new features for the **Yoxi (ride-hailing platform)** CMS frontend and backend.
- Led the design of the software architecture for a logistics fleet management SaaS product built **from 0 to 1**, including tenant management, subscription tier management, 100+ critical features, and out-of-the-box capabilities.
- Strategically used **design patterns** and chose **NestJS** to facilitate the implementation of **clean architecture principles**, enhancing code maintainability, scalability.
- Overcame the challenge of manual propagation in asynchronous context tracking by using AsyncLocalStorage and Proxy objects to achieve efficient retrieval of tenant-specific data, such as user and database connection.
- Improved system scalability and reliability by introducing **RabbitMQ** as a distributed message system for tenant management and asynchronous events.
- Optimized order creation by implementing a Redis-based solution to prevent race conditions and boosted database query performance by 60% by refactoring SQL.
- Designed unit tests to ensure code quality by using **Jest**, with 95% coverage for accounting-related functions.
- Leveraged **RxJS** for complex report generation, improving code maintainability and reducing complexity.
- Halved docker image size and 40% faster Jenkins deployments, by migrating npm to pnpm.

Full Stack Intern, Memopresso, Taipei, Taiwan

2021.04 - 2021.08

- Built a custom clothing and accessories design website with Next is and Redux, used by over 10,000 users.
- Leveraged Strapi as a content management system, saving 50% on backend development and maintenance time, while simplifying workload for operations staff.

Education

National Taipei University of Technology

2017 - 2021

B.S., Computer Science and Information Engineering - GPA 3.69/4

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals / AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner 2023.10
TOEIC - Score 840 2023.05